Hotel Chevalier is a drama, romance film directed by Wes Anderson.
In a Paris hotel room, Jack Whitman lies on a bed.
His phone rings; it's a woman on her way to see him, a surprise.
She arrives and the complications of their
relationship emerge in bits and pieces.
Will they make love?
Is their relationship over?
(A prequel to The Darjeeling Limited, 2007.)
Jack Whitman, played by Jason Schwartzman.
Jack's Girlfriend, played by Natalie Portman.
Security, played by Waris Ahluwalia.
Waiter, played by Michel Castejon.
Hotel Chevalier is a 2007 short film written and directed by Wes Anderson.
Starring Jason Schwartzman and Natalie Portman as former lovers who reunite in a Paris hotel room, the
13-minute film acts as a prologue to Anderson's 2007 feature The Darjeeling Limited.
It was shot on location in a Parisian hotel by a small crew and self-financed by
Anderson, who initially intended it to be a stand-alone work.
Its first showing was at the Venice Film Festival premiere of the feature film on September 2,
2007, and it made its own debut later that month at Apple Stores in four U.S.
The day after the film's premiere, it was made freely available from the iTunes Store for
one month, during which time it was downloaded more than 500,000 times.
The film garnered acclaim from reviewers, who compared it favorably to The Darjeeling
Limited and praised its richness, poignancy, and careful construction.
The film explores themes of hotel room, depression,
paris, france, balcony, girlfriend.
The tone is emotional.